# **ERIK KIMSEY**

### **///** SOFTWARE ENGINEER

### erikkimsey.com

T: 540 278 4525 E: kimseyerik@gmail.com

github.com/erikkimsey linkedin.com/in/erikkimsey

As a passionate, tenacious, and creative engineer, I use the right tools and architecture for the job. But, I specialize in full-stack engineering using ES6/7, React, NodeJS, and PostgreSQL, with a passion for building intuitive, performant, and beautiful technology.

### SKILLS

### **Full-Stack Engineering**

- · JavaScript, React, NextJS
- Redux
- CSS3, Sass, Styled-Componets
- HTML5
- NodeJS, Express API
- Relational & NoSQL Database
- GraphQL
- Apollo-Server / -Client
- Python / Django
- Webpack
- · Test-Driven Development
- Bootstrap
- Redis
- Web Audio API
- Web Sensor APIs
- P5.is
- D3.js

### Languages

- Javascript (ES6/7)
- Python
- · SQL
- GraphQL
- · Java (Android)
- Processing
- · C/C++

### **Design Tools**

- · Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe InDesign
- Adobe XD

### Misc. (experience varying)

- · React-Native
- Propellerhead Reason
- Abelton Live
- Audacity
- Blender
- Unity3D
- JUCE
- Arduino
- · Adobe Premiere
- · Adobe AfterEffects
- ARCore

# WORK EXPERIENCE

### 9/2018

### **NEXTLEVEL / KARDION**

### Front-End Engineer

### (HTML5, Sass, Bootstrap)

 Per design specifications, helped build responsive website for Kardion GmbH

### 6/2018

### **NEXTLEVEL / B612 DESIGN**

#### **Front-End Engineer**

### (Angular 4 & D3)

 Contributed to the development of an interactive guilloche for use by a Stuttgart design firm, B612

### 1/2018

### RAINCROW

# Back-End Engineer contractor (NodeJS & Redis)

 Contributed to the early-stage design and development of a Node server supporting the activity of a MMORPG (Covens)

### 10/2016 - 6/2017

### **CHARTIQ**

### JavaScript Engineer

### (JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, & AngularJS)

- Helped implement "ProCharts" into a client eToro AngularJS application
- Helped build and debug of ChartIQ's flagship financial-charting solution
- Contributed to public-facing documentation

### 2012 - 2016

### **ROSETTA STONE**

### Studio Recording Technician/ Product Support

- Monitored and recorded Live Studio Sessions.
- Created training materials for Studio Recording Technician role.
- Helped Consumers Troubleshoot Rosetta Stone software issues

# EDUCATION

### 2018 - 2019

### **COMPUTER SCIENCE**

Lambda School

Curriculum:

- Full-Stack Web Development
- Database and RESTful API Design
- Programming paradigms (Declarative, Imperative, and Procedural)
- · Software Design Patterns
- Single-Page Application Development
- Algorithm Analysis
- Data Structures
- Theory of Computation
- · Computer Architecture
- Cellular Automata
- Version Control
- Agile (Scrum and Kanban) and Waterfall techniques

### 2017

### **COMPUTER SCIENCE**

### OSU

- · Object-Oriented Programming in C++
- Discrete Maths

### 2006 - 2010

### PHILOSOPHY (BS)

James Madison University

Minors: creative writing & design

- Phi Sigma Tau Philosophy Honors Society Member
- Director of the Club of Creative Writing

### 2011

### WEB DESIGN & DEVELOPMENT (CERT)

Blue Ridge Community College

- Javascript, HTML, CSS, Java
- · Graphic Design Concepts
- Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign